QUAN TENG FOONG

+65 9797 4635

quantf@u.nus.edu · LinkedIn · GitHub

I am currently pursuing a Bachelor of Computing in Computer Science at the National University of Singapore (NUS). I have experience in Software Engineering and working in team projects. I am dependable, tenacious and diligent. My areas of interest include Artificial Intelligence and Software Engineering.

EXPERIENCE

MAY 2022 - OCT 2022

ROBOT NAVIGATION INTERN, CONTINENTAL

- Worked on Visual Simultaneous Localisation and Mapping (vSLAM) algorithms on Continental's last-mile delivery robot, Corriere.
- Worked with Intel Realsense RGB-D cameras (camera calibration, 3D Computer Vision).
- Technologies: Robot Operating System (ROS), Docker

AUG 2021 - NOV 2021

TEACHING ASSISTANT (PROGRAMMING METHODOLGY), NUS

- Conducted weekly tutorial sessions on programming and computational problem solving for Computer Science freshmen.
- Graded and provided feedback on weekly programming assignments.
- Provided consultation sessions outside of class.

EDUCATION

AUG 2020 - PRESENT

BACHELOR OF COMPUTING, NUS

- CAP: 4.28/5.00
- Expected graduation: May 2024
- Co-curricular Activities: NUS Canoe Sprint Team
- Achievements:
 - Sliver and Bronze medals in Inter-Tertiary Canoeing Championships (2022)
 - o 4th place in the Inter-Tertiary Canoeing Championships (2021)

FEB 2016 - DEC 2017

GCE A-LEVELS, ANGLO-CHINESE JUNIOR COLLEGE

- Rank points: 88.75/90
- Achievements:
 - ACJC Merit Sports Award (2017)
 - Singapore Schools Sports Council Colours Award (2017)
 - Edusave Certificate of Academic Achievement (2016 & 2017)

JAN 2012 - DEC 2015

GCE O-LEVELS, CATHOLIC HIGH SCHOOL

- Achievements:
 - NCC Overall Outstanding Cadet Award (2015)
 - Edusave Award for Achievement, Good Leadership & Service (2015)
 - o Catholic High School Chong Seak Chan Award (2015)

PROJECTS

AUG 2022 - PRESENT

CAROUSELL SCRAPER

- A web scraper with a telegram bot frontend for the online second-hand market, Carousell.
- Technologies: BeautifulSoup, python-telegram-bot, crontab

JUL 2022 - PRESENT

MIDDLE JUNCTURE

- My own implementation of Apple's Center Stage, allowing the user's webcam to zoom in and track his/her face.
- Technologies: dlib face recognition, OpenCV

APR 2022 - MAY 2022

HARD DISK PREDICTIVE MAINTENANCE

- Worked with a team of 5 to train machine learning models to predict hard disk failure for predictive maintenance.
- Technologies: sklearn, pandas, numpy
- Report

MAY 2021 - AUG 2021

FRIENDS.

- An all-in-one package for on-the-fly, school-based networking.
- Developed at the height of the COVID-19 pandemic to allow University students to make friends despite not meeting up face-to-face.
- Technologies: Django, HTML, CSS
- Github link

SKILLS

- Object-Oriented Programming
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Java, Python, C, C++, MIPS
- Computer-Aided Design
- Docker
- sklearn

- Teamwork
- Communication
- Problem Solving
- Linux
- Robot Operating System
- OpenCV